Qin Wu 吴 琴

86-18108186998 (China) xiduowawa@gmail.com http://imslab.design

Chengdu University of Information Technology No.24 Block 1, Xuefu Road, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China, 610225

Last Updated: October 27, 2018



RESEARCH INTEREST

Keywords:

Human Computer Interaction, Interactive media, User experience

Summary:

I am committed to the intersection of computer science and art design, mostly in the direction of human-computer interaction design. I have a lot of experience in the teaching of human-computer interaction, interactive art of lights and shadows, intelligent hardware design, user experience design etc. I also studied the design and development of educational robots.

EDUCATION

National Taiwan University of Science and Technology, Taiwan

Aug. 2017-Present

Department of Computer Science and Information Engineering

Ph.D. Student,

Advisor: Prof. Shin-Ming Cheng

Tsinghua University, Beijing, China

Aug. 2013-Jun. 2016

Department of Information Art & Design, Interactive Design Institute

M.S. in Fine Arts,

Advisor: Prof. Qiong Wu

Chengdu University of Information Technology, Chengdu, China

Sept. 2008-Jun. 2012

WORK EXPERIENCES

• Lecturer, Department of Computer Science, CHENGDU UNIVERSITY OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Chengdu, China, Jul. 2016-Present

• User experience Intern, User Experience Design Group, LINKEDIN CHINA

Beijing, China, Nov.2015- Feb.2016

• Interaction design Intern, Department of service design, LENOVO

Beijing, China, Jun.2015- Sept. 2015

• UI design Intern, XUETANG X

Beijing, China, Sept. 2014- Feb. 2015

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

• Team leader, Interactive Media Studio, Chengdu University of Information Technology, China

Nov. 2016-Present

- Project 1: MagicPAPER: Tabletop Interactive Projection Device Based on Kraft Paper
- Project 2: Anmoji: A massage robot based on head and shoulders control
- Project 3: A study of the interactive design of the Qiang culture in China
- Project video list: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLodCiLjz-NeDSO-KHqLMuVKp5S 8-CWE
- Research Assistant, Human machine control research Lab, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shenzhen, China

Jul. 2017-Present

-Advisors: Prof. Xiping Hu, Prof. Jun Cheng

Publicity Chair, ACM China

Oct. 2016- April 2018

-With: Prof.Yunhao Liu

-Service: All visual design at ACM TURC 2017

-Service: Design at ACM TURC 2018

• Research Assistant, Collaborative Innovation Center for Image and Geospatial Information, Chengdu University of Information Technology, Chengdu, China

Jul. 2016-Present

Advisors: Prof. Jiliu Zhou

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- Course Teacher, INFORMATION ARCHITECTURE AND VISUALIZATION (Junior Required course)
 - -Digital Media Technology Institute at Chengdu University of Information Technology, Autumn 2016
- Course Teacher, USER RESEARCH AND VALUE CREATE (Senior Elective course)
 - School of Computer Science at Chengdu University of Information Technology, Spring 2017
- Course Teacher, FUNDAMENTALS OF COLLEGE COMPUTERS (A) (Freshmen Required course)
 - School of Computer Science at Chengdu University of Information Technology, Autumn 2018

AWARDS

- "Honorable Mention Award-Demo" ACM SUI 2018
- "SIC People's Choice Honorable Mention Award" ACM UIST 2018

PUBLICATIONS

- Wu Qin, Jiashuo Cao, Chuang Zhou, Ji Huang, Zhuo Li, Shin-Ming Cheng, Jun Cheng, and Guanghui Pan. "Intelligent Smoke Alarm System with Wireless Sensor Network Using ZigBee." *Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing* 2018 (2018).
- Qin Wu, Sirui Wang, Jiayuan Wang, Jia-shuo Cao, Xing-Yuan Huang, and Rung-Huei Liang.
 MagicPAPER: An Integrated Shadow-Art Hardware Device Enabling Touch Interaction on Paper.
 In Proceedings of the 2018 ACM Conference Companion Publication on Designing Interactive Systems (DIS '18).
- Zheng, Jianbo, Qieshi Zhang, Shihao Xu, Hong Peng, and Qin Wu. "Cognition-Based Context-Aware Cloud Computing for Intelligent Robotic Systems in Mobile Education." *IEEE Access* 6 (2018): 49103-49111.
- Sirui Wang, Jiayuan Wang, and Qin Wu*. MagicPAPER: An Integrated Shadow-Art Hardware Device Enabling Touch Interaction on Kraft paper. In Proceedings of the Symposium on Spatial User Interaction (SUI '18).

- Yuwei Li, Chenmei Yu, Zhen Yang, Ziyue Guo, and **Qin Wu***. See Your Voice: An Interactive Device of Speech Visualisations for Users with Poor Hearing. *In Proceedings of the Sixth International Symposium of Chinese CHI* (ChineseCHI '18).
- Qin Wu, Fanglve Zhang, Sihan Zhou, Yuehao Qin, and Xi Wu. Table War: A Tower-Defense Game Device with Augmented Reality Projection. *In Proceedings of the Sixth International Symposium of Chinese CHI* (ChineseCHI '18).
- Qin Wu, Sirui Wang, Jiayuan Wang. MagicPAPER: Tabletop Interactive Projection Device Based on Kraft Paper. (ISS '18 accepted).